### Xenia Cher

+31649818794 · xeniacherpm@gmail.com · <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/xenia-cheremnykh">https://xenia-cher.tilda.ws/</a> · Amsterdam, Netherlands

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

**Product Owner** with a **4-year** track record in optimizing product value and leading high-performing Scrum teams. Executed and analyzed **50+ experiments**. Successfully launched **7 niche travel and edtech products** from hypothesis to MVP, targeting **global markets**. Managed **20+ edtech projects** and advanced 1 to the finals of a national grant competition.

- Drove a **60% increase** in end-to-end conversion rate;
- Achieved a substantial **42% growth** in user base through SEO enhancements;
- Elevated yearly revenue by 18% within the initial year through the introduction of a novel type of product.

Authorized to work for any employer in the Netherlands. No visa sponsorship is required.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Product Owner

February 2022 - December 2023

Marketnet Technologies, Dubai, UAE

IT solutions for the travel industry to a worldwide audience

- Improved end-to-end conversion rate by **60% YoY** through exhaustive A/B testing and implementation of winning variations:
- Steered end-to-end development of **12 product features**, orchestrating collaboration among cross-functional teams of **designers and engineers**;
- Launched a personalized recommendation engine using **customized algorithms**, keeping customers engaged for **26% longer** each session;
- Drove a 17% increase in registration conversions by optimizing and simplifying user onboarding flow;
- Forged strategic partnerships with leading market companies, **expanding user base by 30%** and driving a **13% increase** in annual recurring revenue;
- Conducted continuous **customer research** through **surveys and interviews** to ensure the product evolved to meet user needs.

#### **Product Owner**

January 2021 - February 2022

Taiga CRM, Perm, Russia

IT solutions for the travel industry to the Russian market

- Boosted amount of users by 42% by leading the implementation of features to improve SEO indicators in
  collaboration with the marketing team as a result, the company occupied the 1st position in search results on Google
  and Yandex in priority search queries;
- Conducted a comprehensive needs analysis and introduced a new type of product, resulting in an **18% increase** in annual revenue in the first year;
- Prioritized and managed key features in the **product roadmap** to reduce the time-to-launch value.

# **Project Manager**

May 2019 - January 2021

Lyceum 4, Perm, Russia

Education organization

- Managed **20+ projects**, including national initiatives such as the student startup accelerator (with 100 members) and the school messenger (with 120 members);
- Developed **3 products** aimed at enhancing the tech sector, submitted them for a grant, and 1 of them advanced to the final round;
- Created and implemented a brand book, including the emblem, logo, typography, souvenirs, and social networks.

# **EDUCATION**

- National Research University Higher School of Economics, Moscow, Russia. Master's Degree, Project Management
- National Research University Higher School of Economics, Moscow, Russia. Bachelor's Degree, Management.

#### **SKILLS**

Agile Methodology (Kanban, Scrum), Product Backlog Management, Prioritization, Release Management, Business Analytics, Technical Specification, Business Requirements, Product Management, Project Management, Data Analysis, Market Research, UX Research, Product Roadmap, Communication Skills, Cross-functional Team Leadership, Attention to Detail, Analytical Thinking, Time Management, Team Collaboration, Problem-solving.